9thelm.com 2015-03-19

# Privacy Policy

**Your privacy is critically important to us. At 9thandelm** **  we have a few fundamental principles:**

  1. We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. 

  2. We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.

  3. We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.

  4. In our Web site, we aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what’s visible to the public, seen by search engines, kept private, and permanently deleted.

Below is our privacy policy which incorporates these goals:

9th and Elm Inc. d/b/a 9thandelm.com (“9thandelm.com”) operates the website http://www.9thandelm.com. It is 9thandelm.com’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our website.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, 9thandelm.com collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. 9thandelm.com’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how 9thandelm.com’s visitors use its website. From time to time, 9thandelm.com may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

9thandelm.com also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. 9thandelm.com does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to 9thandelm.com’s websites choose to interact with 9thandelm.com in ways that require 9thandelm.com to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that 9thandelm.com gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a blog at 9thandelm.com to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with 9thandelm.com– by submitting a request to a Service Provider, for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal information required to process those transactions. In each case, 9thandelm.com collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with 9thandelm.com. 9thandelm.com does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Aggregated Statistics**

9thandelm.com may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, 9thandelm.com may monitor the most popular services on the 9thandelm.com site. 9thandelm.com may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, 9thandelm.com does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

9thandelm.com discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on 9thandelm.com’s behalf or to provide services available at 9thandelm.com’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using 9thandelm.com’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. 

9thandelm.com will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, 9thandelm.com discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when 9thandelm.com believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of 9thandelm.com, third parties or the public at large. 

For Service Providers, we may use financial information or payment method to process payment for any purchases made on our website, to pre-qualify Service Providers to participate in our service network, to protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions, and otherwise as needed to manage our business.

If you are a registered user of a 9thandelm.com website and have supplied your email address, 9thandelm.com may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with 9thandelm.com. 

If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. 

9thandelm.com takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. 9thandelm.com uses cookies to help 9thandelm.com identify and track visitors, their usage of 9thandelm.com website, and their website access preferences. 9thandelm.com visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using 9thandelm.com’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of 9thandelm.com’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Ads**

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by 9thandelm.com and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, 9thandelm.com may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in 9thandelm.com’s sole discretion. 9thandelm.com encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a 9thandelm.com account, you should also check your blog’s dashboard for alerts to these changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
